<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en"/>
  <language culture="de-DE"/>

  <introduction lang="en">
    The Bitcoin-Transaction-Viewer displays the most important information about a transaction.
    <newline/>
    In the upper half of the viewer information about the transaction. 
    For example, the hash value, fee or timestamp of the transaction. The names are taken directly 
    from the Json strings of Blockchain. The lower half lists all inputs and outputs processed in this transaction.
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Der Bitcoin-Transaktions-Betrachter zeigt die wichtigsten Informationen von einer Transaktion an.
    <newline/>
    In der oberen Hälfte des Betrachters stehen Informationen zur Transaktion. Zum Beispiel den Hashwert, Gebühr oder den Zeitstempel der Transaktion.
    Die Bezeichnungen sind direkt aus den Json Strings der Blockchain übernommen. In der unteren Hälfte werden alle Eingänge und Ausgänge aufgelistet die in dieser
    Transaktion verarbeitet wurden.
  </introduction>

  <usage lang="en">
    The Bitcoin transaction viewer has two inputs. In the first entrance, the transaction itself is sent and in the second, 
    still excessively, the information of the transaction exits. Since the data for this is not completely present in the actual transaction.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Der Bitcoin-Transaktions-Betrachter hat zwei Eingänge. Im ersten Eingang wird die Transaktion selbst verschickt und im zweiten
    noch zuästzlich die Informationen der Transaktionsausgänge. Da die Daten hierzu nicht vollständig in der eigentlichen 
    Transaktion vorhanden sind.
  </usage>
  
  <presentation lang="en">
    There are no interactive fields in the presentation. The data is only displayed legibly.
  </presentation>
  
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
    In der Präsentation gibt es keine interaktiven Felder. Die Daten werden nur gut lesbar dargestellt.
  </presentation>
  
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/gettxout" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Here the used Bitcoin API is made available on a website (gettxout)</caption>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/gettxout" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Hier wird die verwendete Bitcoin API auf einer Website bereitgestellt (gettxout)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/getrawtransaction" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Here the used Bitcoin API is made available on a website (getrawtransaction)</caption>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/getrawtransaction" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Hier wird die verwendete Bitcoin API auf einer Website bereitgestellt (getrawtransaction)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>