<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en"/>


  <introduction lang="en">
    There are two people, Alice and Bob. Alice knows secret magic password, which opens a door in magic cave. Bob doesn´t believe Alice that she knows this secret.
    Alice don´t want to tell her secret to Bob, she just want to proof him, that she knows it. So they make a deal, Alice will go to the cave, with one of n entrances. Entrances are connected, but there is a magic door between them. Bob doesn´t know the entrance, which Alice entered the cave. Bob just shout the name of entrace and Alice must go out by named entrance. If she know magic password, she can go through the door a leave the cave with named entrace. If she doesn´t know magic password, she must be lucky, she can bluff that she know the secret only if Bob name her entrance. They repeat this until Bob is convinced that Alice knows the secret. 
    And this problem solves Zero-Knowledge protocol. This plugin represent Bob. Bob want for Alice to prove him, that she knows the secret. So she send her number, if Alice knows the secret, she can send him that number easily back. But if she doesn´t know the secret, she must be lucky a guess that number from ammount of options. Bob will make certain ammount of attempts. If Alice send him wrong number, it means that she doesn´t know the secret. If Alice send him right number for every time, she convince Bob that she knows the secret. 
  </introduction>



  <usage lang="en">
    This plugin represent Alice.
    After dragging the Zero Knowledge Checked component onto the workspace, you need to specify two inputs. Both inputs are from Zero Knowledge Checker. First input is wanted number, that Bob from Alice want. Second input is information about ammount of options. You can set up if Alice knows secret. If she knows the secret, she will always send Bob same number. If she doesn´t know secret, she will generate random number from 1 to ammount of options and that number she will send to Bob. 
  </usage>

  
  <presentation lang="en">
  </presentation>
  

  
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero-knowledge_proof" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Zero-Knowledge</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>