<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en"/>
  <language culture="de-DE"/>

  <introduction lang="en">
    The Bitcoin-Transaction-Downloader downloads a transaction from the Bitcoin Blockchain.
    <newline />
         To use this downloader you need access to a server / client that has the complete blockchain stored.
    It is important that this server is started with certain parameters.
         <newline />
         -server<newline />
         -rpcuser=%USERNAME<newline />
         -rpcpassword=%PASSWORD<newline />
         -rpcport=%PORTNUMBER<newline />
         -txindex<newline />
         <newline />
         With the access data you can then query the blockchain using API.
    Particularly important is the -txindex, otherwise not all transactions will be downloaded,
    which can lead to errors.
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Der Bitcoin-Transaktions-Downlader läd eine Transaction von der Bitcoin Blockchain herunter.
    <newline/>
    Um diesen Downloader zu benutzen benötigt man Zugriff auf einen Server/Client der die komplette Blockchain
    gespeichert hat. Dabei ist wichtig das dieser Server mit bestimmten Parametern gestartet wird.
    <newline/>
    -server<newline/>
    -rpcuser=%USERNAME<newline/>
    -rpcpassword=%PASSWORD<newline/>
    -rpcport=%PORTNUMMER<newline/>
    -txindex<newline/>
    <newline/>
    Mit dem Zugangsdaten kann man dann die Blockchain mittels API abfragen. Besonders wichtig ist der -txindex,
    sonst werden nicht alle Transaktionen heruntergeladen, was zu Fehlern führen kann.
  </introduction>

  <usage lang="en">
    The Bitcoin Transaction Downloader needs a transaction hash to download the information. 
    Then the information about the transaction and the relevant information about the related transaction exits are provided.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Der Bitcoin-Transaktions-Downloader benötigt einen Transaktionshash um die Informationen herunterladen zu können.
    Bereit gestellt werden dann die Informationen zur Transaktion und die relevanten Informationen zu den dazugehörigen
    Transaktionsausgängen.
  </usage>
  
  <presentation lang="en">
  </presentation>
  
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
  </presentation>
  
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/gettxout" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Here the used Bitcoin API is made available on a website (gettxout)</caption>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/gettxout" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Hier wird die verwendete Bitcoin API auf einer Website bereitgestellt (gettxout)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/getrawtransaction" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Here the used Bitcoin API is made available on a website (getrawtransaction)</caption>
      <link url="http://chainquery.com/bitcoin-api/getrawtransaction" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Hier wird die verwendete Bitcoin API auf einer Website bereitgestellt (getrawtransaction)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>