<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sample>
  <title lang="en">DES-Cipher</title>
  <description lang="en">This template shows how to use the <i>DES-Cipher</i>.<newline /><newline />
The Data Encryption Standard (DES) is a block cipher that uses shared secret encryption. It was selected by the National Bureau of Standards as an official Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS) for the United States in 1976 and which has subsequently enjoyed widespread use internationally. It is based on a symmetric-key algorithm that uses a 56-bit key. The algorithm was initially controversial because of classified design elements, a relatively short key length, and suspicions about a National Security Agency (NSA) backdoor. DES consequently came under intense academic scrutiny which motivated the modern understanding of block ciphers and their cryptanalysis.<newline /><newline />
DES is now considered to be insecure for many applications. This is chiefly due to the 56-bit key size being too small; in January, 1999, distributed.net and the Electronic Frontier Foundation collaborated to publicly break a DES key in 22 hours and 15 minutes (see chronology). There are also some analytical results which demonstrate theoretical weaknesses in the cipher, although they are infeasible to mount in practice. The algorithm is believed to be practically secure in the form of Triple DES, although there are theoretical attacks. In recent years, the cipher has been superseded by the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES). Furthermore, DES has been withdrawn as a standard by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (formerly the National Bureau of Standards).<newline /><newline />
In some documentation, a distinction is made between DES as a standard and DES the algorithm which is referred to as the DEA (the Data Encryption Algorithm). When spoken, "DES" is either spelled out as an abbreviation (/ˌdiːˌiːˈɛs/), or pronounced as a one-syllable acronym (/ˈdɛz/).<newline /><newline />
Source: <external ref="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Encryption_Standard" /></description>
  <keywords>symmetric, standard, 56, NSA</keywords>
  <title lang="de">DES-Chiffre</title>
  <description lang="de">Diese Vorlage zeigt die Verwendung der <i>DES-Ver-/Entschlüsselung</i>.<newline /><newline />
Der Data Encryption Standard (DES) ist ein weit verbreiteter symmetrischer Verschlüsselungsalgorithmus.<newline /><newline />
Der DES-Algorithmus wurde als offizieller Standard für die US-Regierung (siehe FIPS 46) im Jahr 1976 bestätigt und wird seither international vielfach eingesetzt. Seine Entstehungsgeschichte hat wegen der Beteiligung der NSA am Design des Algorithmus immer wieder Anlass zu Spekulationen über seine Sicherheit gegeben. Heute wird DES aufgrund der verwendeten Schlüssellänge von nur 56 Bits für viele Anwendungen als nicht ausreichend sicher erachtet.<newline /><newline />
Die Schlüssellänge kann durch Mehrfachanwendung des DES jedoch auf einfache Weise vergrößert werden. Als Triple-DES, auch als TDES, 3DES oder DESede bezeichnet, wird der DES weiterhin am häufigsten, zum Beispiel von Banken in Chipkartenanwendungen, eingesetzt, obwohl der TDES als offizieller Standard für die USA durch den Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) abgelöst wurde.<newline /><newline />
Quelle: <external ref="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Encryption_Standard" /></description>
  <keywords lang="de">symmetrisch</keywords>
  <icon file="DES_Sample.png" />
  <relevantPlugins>
    <plugin name="DES" />
  </relevantPlugins>
</sample>
