<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sample>

  <title lang="en">BB84 Key Exchange with eavesdropping attack</title>
  <summary lang="en">Usage of the <i>BB84 Key Exchange and its attack</i></summary>
  <description lang="en">BB84 Key Exchange is a photon-based method of exchanging cryptographic keys.
  It is one of the earliest practical examples of key exchange implemented within the field of cryptography.
  The BB84-Protocol is one of the most recent cryptographic procedures on the base of quantum physics. A key is sent through unsecure channel via polarized photons. A man in the middle tries catch these transmitted photons. After
  checking if the key is secure, it can then be used to encrypt subsequent communications using a symmetric key cipher.<newline /><newline />
  Source: <external ref="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BB84" /></description>
  <keywords>protocol, bennet, brassard, 1984, photon, photons, polarization, light, quantum, physics, alice, bob, eve</keywords>

  <title lang="de">BB84-Schlüsselaustausch mit Lauschangriff</title>
  <summary lang="de">Anwenden des <i>B84-Schlüsselaustauschs und eines Angriffsversuchs</i></summary>
  <description lang="de">Das BB84-Protokoll stellt eines der modernsten kryptographischen Verfahren auf Basis der Quantenphysik dar. Mit Hilfe von polarisierten Photonen wird ein Schlüssel über einen öffentlichen, 
  unsicheren Kanal ausgetauscht. Ein Mittelsmann versucht, diese Photonen abzufangen. Nachdem der Schlüssel empfangen wird, wird er auf seine Sicherheit geprüft und kann im Anschluss für die Anwendung einer symmetrischen Chiffre verwendet werden. <newline /><newline />
  Quelle: <external ref="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantenschl%C3%BCsselaustausch" /></description>
  <keywords lang="de">protokoll, schlüssel, photonen, polarisation, licht, quanten, physik, alice, bob, eve</keywords>

  <icon file="BB84-Key-Exchange + Attack.png" />

  <relevantPlugins>
    <plugin name="BB84ErrorDetector" />
    <plugin name="BB84KeyGenerator" />
    <plugin name="BB84ManInTheMiddle" />
    <plugin name="BB84PhotonDecoder" />
	<plugin name="BB84PhotonEncoder" />
	<plugin name="BB84PhotonbaseGenerator" />
  </relevantPlugins>

</sample>
