<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<documentation>
  <language culture="en"/>
  <language culture="de-DE"/>

  <introduction lang="en">
    RSA is an asymmetric algorithm devoloped 1977 by Ronald L. Rivest, Adi Shamir und Leonard Adleman at the Massachusetts Institute of
    Technology. It is known as the first published asymmetric algorithm. The security of RSA is based on the factorization
    problem and the assumption that there is no suitable algorithm to factorize a big number in suitable time
    (this means that a factorization is finished not in centuries but in realistic time like hours or days).
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="de-DE"> 
    RSA ist ein asymmetrischer Algorithmus, der 1977 von Ronald L. Rivest, Adi Shamir und Leonard Adleman am Massachusetts Institute
    of Technology entwickelt wurde. Er ist als der erste asymmetrische Algorithmus bekannt. Die Sicherheit von RSA basiert auf dem
    Faktorisierungs-Problem und der Annahme, dass es keinen "schnellen" Algorithmus gibt, um große Zahlen in annehmbarer Zeit zu
    faktorisieren ( "Annehmbare Zeit" meint hier, dass die Faktorisierung nicht in Jahren/Jahrhunderten sondern in einer 
    "realistischen" Zeit wie etwa Tagen oder Stunden durchgeführt wird ).
  </introduction>

  <usage lang="en">
    The RSA plugin has two ways to be used (you can use only one or both simultaneouly): The user is able to use RSA to encrypt 
    and decrypt just big integers on the one hand and he is able to encrypt and decrypt texts using the RSA algorithm on the 
    other hand.
    To encrypt/decrypt numbers the user has to add a Big Number Input m/c representing our message m or our ciphertext c
    and an output big integer representing the output message m or the output ciphertext c. He has also to add a Big Number
    Input N representing the N of the RSA algorithm. And the last input he has to add is a Big Number Input E / D which
    represents the public or the private key depending on en- or decryption. To encrypt/decrypt texts the user has to add
    an input byte array and an output byte array. Also the direction (en- or decrypt) has to be set in the plugins options.
    He has also to add a Big Number Input N representing our the N of the RSA algorithm. And the last input he has to add is
    a Big Number Input E / D which represents the public or the private key depending on en- or decryption.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Das RSA Plugin beinhaltet zwei Nutzungsarten (welche auch parallel genutzt werden können): Der Benutzer kann zum einen
    große Zahlen ver- und entschlüsseln als auch ganze Texte ver- und entschlüsseln. Um große Zahlen zu ver- und entschlüsseln
    muss der Benutzer den Zahleneingang m oder c, der die Nachricht m oder den verschlüsselten Text c repräsentiert. Desweiteren
    muss der Benutzer den m oder c Zahlenausgang verbinden, aus dem die ver- oder entschlüsselte Nachricht herauskommt. Für die
    Berechnung müssen außerdem der Eingang N und die Schlüsseleingänge E oder D verbunden werden. E ist der öffentliche Schlüssel
    und D entsprechend der private Schlüssel. Um ganze Text zu ver- oder entschlüsseln, kann der Benutzer alternativ einen Texteingang
    sowie einen Textausgang anschließen. In den Eintstellungen des Plugins muss zu guter Letzt, zumindest für die Textver- und 
    Textentschlüsselung eingestellt werden ob Ver- oder Entschlüsselt werden soll.
  </usage>
  
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA"/>
      <caption lang="en">RSA in the english wikipedia</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA-Kryptosystem"/>
      <caption lang="de-DE">RSA-Kryptosystem in der deutschen Wikipedia</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>