<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<documentation>
  <language culture="en"/>
  <language culture="de-DE"/>

  <introduction lang="en">
    This component produces various kinds of random values.
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Diese Komponente erzeugt verschiedene Arten von Zufallswerten.
  </introduction>

  <usage lang="en">
    The component offers the following kinds of random values on its outputs:

    <list>
      <item>
        A sequence of random bytes is available at the outputs <b>ByteArray Output</b> and <b>Stream Output</b>. The length of the sequence can be determined in the settings of the component. It must lie between 1 and 10.000.000.
      </item>
      <item>
        A random boolean value (<i>true</i> or <i>false</i>) is provided at the <b>Boolean Output</b>.
      </item>
      <item>
        A random integer value from the interval [0,2147483647] is provided at the <b>Number Output</b>.
      </item>
      <item>
        A list of random numbers from the interval [0,2147483647] is provided at the <b>Number List Output</b>. The length of the list can be determined in the settings of the component. It must lie between 1 and 1.000.000.
      </item>
    </list>

    The component has a dynamic and a static operating mode. When the dynamic mode is selected, the component
    creates a new random values every time it is started. When the static mode is selected, the
    random values are only created once and reused in subsequent starts of the component. The operating mode
    can be selected in the settings tab of the component.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="de-DE">
    An den Ausgängen dieser Komponente liegen folgende Zufallswerte an:
    
    <list>
      <item>
        An den Ausgängen <b>Ausgabedaten als Byte-Array</b> und <b>Ausgabedatenstrom</b> wird eine Folge von Zufallsbytes ausgegeben. Die Anzahl der zu erzeugenden Bytes kann in den Einstellungen festgelegt werden und muss
        zwischen 1 und 10.000.000 liegen.
      </item>
      <item>
        Am Ausgang <b>Ausgabe Boolescher Wert</b> wird ein zufälliger boolescher Wert (also <i>wahr</i> oder <i>falsch</i>) ausgegeben.
      </item>
      <item>
        Am Ausgang <b>Zahlausgabe</b> wird eine Zufallszahl aus dem Intervall [0,2147483647] ausgegeben.
      </item>
      <item>
        Am Ausgang <b>Zahlenlisteausgabe</b> wird eine Liste von Zufallszahlen aus dem Intervall [0,2147483647] ausgegeben. Die Anzahl der zu erzeugenden Zahlen kann in den Einstellungen festgelegt werden und muss
        zwischen 1 und 1.000.000 liegen.
      </item>
    </list>

    Die Komponente hat eine statische und eine dynamische Betriebsart. In der dynamischen Betriebsart werden
    die Zufallszahlen bei jedem Start der Komponente neu generiert und die Komponente liefert daher jedes Mal neue
    Zufallszahlen. In der statischen Betriebsart werden die einmal erzeugten Werte beibehalten und bei jedem
    Start der Komponente erneut ausgegeben. Die Betriebsart kann in den Einstellungen der Komponente gewählt werden.
  </usage>
 
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_number_generation" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Random number generation</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zufallszahlengenerator" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Zufallszahlengenerator</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>

</documentation>